BHUVANESHWAR.S

+91 9677116127. bhuvaneshwar014@gmail.com Chennai , Tamil Nadu

RPA DEVELOPER

Experienced in building Robotic Automation Processes and Business Objects for various business systems.

Experience in Automating Web portal, Excel and RDP automations for Attended and Un-attended development.

Development and Deployment of bots using UiPath.

Support junior developers implementing, best practices, business, and technical requirements, problem-solving, system testing and bug fixes.

Experience in creating process flows using UiPath Studio, UiPath Robot and Orchestrator in UiPath. Total 2 years of IT experience in Robotic Process Automation (RPA) and overall Experience of 3 years.

SKILLS

RPA - UiPath
Excel Automation
Bot Development

Uipath Studio Uipath orchestrator Re framework Software testing
Agile
Jira

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Wipro Feb 2021 - Present Rpa Developer

July 2023 - Present

Project: UnitedHealth Group

Description: UnitedHealth Group is a health insurance company that also provides data analytics and consulting services to healthcare providers, as well as pharmacy care services. Its principal divisions include UnitedHealthcare, OptumHealth, OptumInsight, and OptumRx.

Responsibilities:

- Used UiPath automation elements such as Mouse, Keyboard and Attribute to automate the desktop sequence activities.
- Developed ROBOTS using UiPath to automate and accelerate 70% of standard business process with minimum human intervention for remaining non-standard processes.
- Implemented selectors for interacting with window and web browsers for continuous navigation of applications.
- Used Screen Scraping method to extract text from running window application by appropriate output methods.
- Used Data Scraping method for extracting structured data from browser applications or documents into a CSV file or Excel Spread sheet.
- Used Excel automation for repetitive Excel data entry, appending and for comparing columns.
- Used UiPath Orchestrator for deployment, monitoring and management of UiPath Robot automation activity.
- Handled exceptions using Try-Catch activity.
- Handled the Execution of project in UiPath Robot.
- Deployed the process in UiPath Orchestrator and scheduled their execution.
- Maintained several RPA Bots as batch processes on daily basis and ensure quality and high performance to the internal and vendor applications of the organization.

Rpa Developer

Project: British telecom October 2022 - July 2023

Description: BT Group plc is a British multinational telecommunications holding company headquartered in London, England. It has operations in around 1 80 countries and is the largest provider offixed-line, broadband and mobile services in the UK, and also provides subscription television and IT services.

Responsibilities:

- Designed and developed automated solutions based on client requirements using UiPath RE-Framework with standard RPA design principles.
- Conducting unit testing and System testing.
- Facilitating Integration and User Acceptance Testing.
- Managing and investigating exceptions. (Business and System Exceptions).
- Supporting existing processes like error fixing and implementing change requirements as a part of structured change control process.
- Fixing bot issues / incident fixes on time and providing workaround to business to run the bot within runtime SLA
- Problem solving issues that arise in day to day running of automation processes and providing timely responses and solutions as required
- Deployment of code through Orchestrator.

STRENGTHS AND EXPERTISE

- Active Listening
- Analytical Skills
- Leadership
- Problem Solving
- Critical Thinking
- Client Relationship Management
- R & D
- Communication
- Operations Management

EDUCATION

ST.PETER'S COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY

Bachelor of Architecture 2015 - 2020